How are you?
>> How are you?
>> You are well.
>> Well, praise the name of the Lord.
>> Amen.
>> I'm glad to see you.
>> You are glad to see me.
>> Yeah. The temperature is a bit cold
here.
July and July. July next week. July.
Tell you whenever the bishop says hi.
I may the bishop says hi.
Hallelujah.
We need to pray. Let's just as we stand
like that, I feel we should just pray
because
la last week has been a bit traumatic
for the nation.
on Friday. Is it Friday when when we not
Thursday me I'm talking about Friday.
Yeah. Friday we we we were going for a
mission withi
someone in Kobangi and it took us three
hours from here to get there because the
road was closed
uh because there were riots of fighting
or something and even yesterday I'm told
it was still bad tear gas was even in
getting to the church who was
ministering
and uh you can see pastor Oscar is
arriving now because Mombasa road has
also been
has been closed by the police,
some construction going on. So, you just
need to pray because uh from here I'm
I'm going to preach in that church. It's
an Accorino church.
>> [applause]
>> Uh, we shall Are you coming with me or
you leave me? You'll come with me. He's
coming with me to make sure that I still
dress like
but they are lovely people. They love
the Lord. They are born again. And I
just enjoyed. We had a great time of
ministry with them. And yesterday I sent
one of my sons to go and minister there
because I was I was in Muen yesterday
near Kadonsi. I went until the morning
came back in the afternoon. So why don't
you just lift this nation before God
that all these things shall be resolved.
We we don't have to keep closing roads,
closing shops, uh closing businesses, uh
closing schools because someone's having
a protest, is having an issue, and
therefore we come on just lift up your
voice. This is what I've been teaching
you all the time. We need to pray so
that we we we can live in peace as a
nation and as a people. Um I I love my
peace. Last Sunday I joined uh pastor uh
George Macharia, pastor Tim Wangi, uh
pastor Pete of Ruak, quite a number of
us who are praying in the streets of
Nairobi. And um come on church, raise
your voice
and just pray for this nation. Pray
for this city. Pray for your county
that these issues shall be resolved
peacefully without breaking into shops,
without burning property, without
burning schools, without uh destroying
um livelihoods, without children missing
school, without us missing to do
business, uh without us missing to uh
important appointments. Some of us need
doctor's appointments and you are told
you cannot go through to see your doctor
because of this and the other. So just
raise your voice and just pray uh this
morning as we before we enter the word.
Father we come before you because you
are a a God who desires as a nation we
live in peace and we live in uh troubers
times but all the same we come before
you. We come before you. We come before
you. And Lord, we just pray in the name
of Jesus Christ that Kenya, Nairobi,
especially our major cities, Mombasa,
Nakuru, Kisumu, Thika, Kakamega, Eldor,
the Kericho. These will be places of
peace for all communities and all people
of this na of this nation that everybody
shall live in peace wherever they are
and not fearing that they have to run
away uh because there's this and that
going on and whatever issues are in this
country father that they shall be
resolved peacefully that's our prayer
they shall be resolved peacefully in
Jesus name I said in Jesus name I say in
Jesus name. Father, just go ahead and
give the Lord a hand clap offering if
you intend to.
[applause]
Father, we not only pray for our nation,
we pray for ourselves and we pray for
ourselves because children have been
here and they have just talked to us
through that presentation. And Lord, we
come to you as parents and we come to
you as fathers especially and praying
for ourselves and praying for fathers in
this house because this nation needs
fathers
and I'm praying that fathers shall
present themselves.
I want you to look around if there's a
man near you uh just uh reach out and
hold your hands and just pray for them.
Those are fathers can pray for another
father. Pray for potential fathers.
Ladies, just pray. Let us pray for the
fathers. Reach out and pray for them
right now. Fatherhood is not just a
privilege. Fatherhood is a
responsibility. And therefore, just
let's pray for fathers. That's our
message will be on fathers this morning.
So let's just pray for them right now.
Mighty God, in the name of Jesus Christ,
we reach out as we pray for the fathers
in this house. We are praying for
fathers all over this nation. Fathers,
these providers, these protectors, these
priests, these prophets. Oh Lord, I am
praying that in the name of Jesus
Christ, their presence shall be felt in
our nation. That is our prayer. That
their presence shall be felt in our
nation, in our community, in our
society, in our homes. that they shall
not just provide, they shall not just
give, they shall but they shall be
present. They shall be present. That is
our prayer. If there's any absentee
father who listening to me in this house
or watching this telecast, but they are
absentee fathers, we reach out to them
right now in the name of Jesus Christ
and pray that God you shall touch them.
you shall minister to them and bring
them back to their families. That is our
prayer and that is our request this
morning in Jesus mighty name. Amen.
[applause]
As we stand like that, let's make our
confession. What do we say? I allow the
word of God to illuminate and enlighten
my path to the principles of his
kingdom. I let go of past traditions and
failures that I've held until today. I
embrace God's principles, new
revelation, and a new mindset. So help
me, God. I am empowered by the Holy
Spirit in every aspect of my life to
live victoriously through God's new
covenant. I'm an adversity to sin,
sickness, poverty, and the ws of the
enemy. I am established and I'm rooted
in his purpose for my life. and I am
transforming my generation. So help me
God in the mighty name of Jesus Christ,
the son of the living God.
>> Amen.
>> And again we said
>> amen.
>> I didn't hear you. And again we say
>> And what do we declare? My life
>> will never
>> ever be the same.
>> Do you believe it?
>> Yes.
>> I'm say do you believe it? Amen.
>> I want only the men to say it. Amen.
What do we say? My life will never ever
be the same again in Jesus name. Amen.
>> Men, are you there?
>> Cuz I want to talk to the men.
Amen.
>> Cuz some of the crisis we having is not
just poor parent parenting is lack of
men, lack of husbands and lack of
fathers. And we need to address
ourselves today from the word of God.
Amen.
>> Amen.
>> Look at two people tell them neighbor
>> and you are my witness.
Somebody say amen.
Let's be seated, please.
I want us to those children. Wasn't that
a great presentation?
>> Do you know what I was seeing right
there when those children were giving
the presentation?
Do do you hear what I'm trying to do did
you realize there was a cry?
>> Yes.
>> Those children were presenting a what? A
cry. Now as this church we had Father's
Day, but on that Father's Day we are
peculiar people. We gave to our ladies
to minister and they did a good job.
Come and talk to me.
But let us not forget the important
message about fathers.
Hallelujah.
>> I said about what?
So you cannot come and tell me me I'm
fatherless. There was a father
because this can I can I continue?
>> This virgin birth happened only once
and that was Jesus Christ was born
by that what do you call it conception
by by conception by the Holy Spirit. But
the rest of us, whether you knew him or
not, there was a father.
The one who sowed the seed,
you may not have known him.
You may never have met him.
And that is a crisis we are having
because we have got a lot of children
who have got fathers they never
experienced, they never knew, they never
met.
And we don't understand the crisis that
that brings in society when fathers are
absent. So let's pick some scriptures.
Shall we do that? I say, shall we do
that?
>> So that we can be able to learn together
the importance of fathers one as a son.
Let's begin from the book of um
Ephesians chapter 6 from verse one. Give
me that in the NIV. Let's see what it
says. Ephesians chapter 6 verse1.
Children, obey your parents in the Lord.
For this is what? Right. Honor whom?
Your father and mother. So they are both
of them there. Which is the first
commandment with a what? With a promise.
That it may go well with you and that
you may enjoy long life on the earth.
Continue. Do you see the verse four?
What does it say?
>> What does it say?
>> Do not do what?
>> Exasperate your children. Instead, bring
them up in the training and the
instruction of the Do you notice that
Paul as when he gets to verse four, he
directs his message to
if you don't repeat, I'll I'll preach
this message with men standing.
So I make sure you are hearing me. So
you don't want me to push me there. So
can you
can I hear your voice?
children to anger instead what bring
them up in the training and instruction
of the Lord. So the means there's a
clear message to one of those parents
and the message to one of those parents
is a parent called who and father and
that's even NKJV says and you I like
that one how how does the King James New
King James put it and you
And you
>> very seriously
>> you fathers
because you are very crucial very very
important
fathers
I was listening to to I was listening to
Greg Lori uh one of my favorite Bible
teachers he's a man called Greg Lori who
leads a church in California
and I was listening to his message on
Father's Day and it and and that's what
challenged me and I said you know what
we are struggling in society because
many things that are happening even in
schools in homes in society
sometime listen to let's be honest it is
it is because of poor parenting but let
me push it further it's because one
parent majorly is missing
in the equation whether it's in Africa
it's in Europe It's in America whatever
when the father is absent
neighbor when you are
when fathers are what absent
in a child's life
it causes a crisis
that's why Paul is praying for families
Ephesians 3:14 Ephesians chapter
Please don't don't leave the sound
alone.
Please go take it back where it was.
What does he say? For this Come on,
church. You already read the scripture.
For this reason, what am I doing? I
kneel before the father
from whom the whole
>> in heaven and EARTH IS WHAT DERIVES ITS
NAME.
A father is such a privilege that entire
family derives their name from Ma.
Many of you do not know Alena's maiden
name.
You just know her as Mrs. Mua.
Am I making sense? But when it comes to
her husband, our admin, we know his full
name, Jackson Malay.
He's deriving his name from his father.
Talk to me. So fathers, fathers, are you
in the house?
>> Father is is a privilege. Is a what? A
privilege. But listen to me friends. The
privilege is only 5%.
95% is what? Responsibility.
Say with me, responsibility.
>> Responsibility.
>> Because we are preaching to men, to
fathers all over. 95% is what?
Responsibility.
SO WHEN FATHERS are absent,
of course we want to give a hand clap to
all the mothers cuz the mothers step in
and they take responsibility. But listen
to me friend, they cannot take your
place.
>> They may work hard. They may provide
food. They may be able to provide some
shelter. They may raise money and even
pay school fees. Even the virtuous woman
MAY EVEN BUY LAND,
BUT THERE'S STILL SOMETHING missing when
a father is absent.
>> My message is fathers are wanted. Yeah.
We we shall put a big poster all over
these big banners that politicians are
now using AND THEY SAY WANTED
FATHERS,
responsible fathers wanted in society.
The statistics show, and I'm quoting my
friend Greg this time, that if you go to
jail, prisons, you'll find that 70% of
the young men incarcerated in jail,
they'll tell you, "I did not have a
father figure in my life."
Even if you go to the juvenile homes,
you'll find they'll tell you, "I did not
have a father figure in my life." Even
the ones on the streets, if you talk to
them, they'll tell you
But they are not living in the real
world. Can I find some real people on
this side?
And they don't know which one of them is
their father.
They just know there's a man who came
and this is and we are forgetting even
on language there's a statement that
says pastor Oscar
My husband,
>> can we talk?
That's why we are missing.
When a man when a man goes on a public
forum and says me, I've got 16 children
with five different women. What kind of
a language is that? And we are
celebrating that person because you have
been able to father 15 children with
five different women. SO ARE YOU TAKING
CARE OF THEM?
Are you present in their lives or you
are just saying me I gave the seed it is
this woman who decided to get pregnant
and she brought this child into the
world but me I don't care because I've
got another woman here and I've got
another woman there and I've got another
woman there. I I am called a a an absent
polygamist.
We have a lot of absent polygamists in
Kenya
and those children grow up without a
father figure in their lives. And the
tragedy I saw in the west is that where
in the socialist countries especially in
Europe when a girl becomes pregnant the
state takes over. They will try to tell
tell that girl, "We'll give you a house.
We'll give you provision. We'll give you
money for shopping.
Talk to me." And one of Can I Can I Can
I say something here?
>> Can I say something here? That is one of
the tragedies of AfricanAmerican history
in the UK in the USA
because when I visited the US for the
first time, this over 36 years ago, I I
was able to learn some of that tragedy
is that when an a woman, white or black,
whatever color, becomes pregnant, the
government is able to provide housing.
Talk to me. They'll provide some
provision. They give her money for
welfare. They'll even pay medical and
all that. But when a man comes into her
life, they withdraw.
Let the man provide.
Now can I continue? So you found that
because of that many Africanamean women
and other minorities, they realize if I
have a man in my life, my house will not
be paid for. I'll not have medical
cover. I'll not have provision. And
these African-American men or minorities
did not have the education
to get good jobs to provide the kind of
housing the government will provide. I
are you understand me now? SO YOU FIND
THAT THIS woman lives in Georgia, but
she has a man in New York who's unknown
to the state of Georgia. That's the one
fathering her children. Yet the state of
Georgia is the one that is providing for
all her needs. So she's raising these
children without a father. So you'll
find many of our African-American
brothers whenever they refer to our
parents says my mama said it
because they never saw a father figure
in their lives.
Am I talking to you?
>> It's a tragedy
because governments ARE NOT SUPPOSED TO
TAKE the place of fathers.
The provider should be a father. Come
and talk to me.
The provider in the home should be what?
A father.
That's what we see in the pro story of
the prodigal son. When the prodigal son
came to his senses, LUKE CHAPTER 5 and
verse 17, the Bible says WHEN HE CAME TO
HIS SENSES, THIS YOUNG MAN says Luke 15
is 15 15:17, sorry. Luke 15:17, Luke
15:17. The Bible says when this young
man came to HIS SENSES HE SAID HOW MANY
WHAT IS THE NEXT 10 say I'm not hearing
you how many
>> does he say of my mothers
>> what does he say my fathers hired
servants
are you getting with the picture now
have food to spare and here I am
starving to CUZ HE REMEMBERED WHEN I WAS
IN my father's house
there was provision
There's inheritance.
Talk to me.
>> Are you hear the PICTURE NOW? SO THIS
YOUNG MAN rises with a negative
mentality. He says I will rise up and go
back to my father. To my father, but
I'll tell him I don't want to BE CALLED
YOUR SON. I WANT TO BE hired as a
servant. BUT THE FATHER had not lost a
servant. He had lost a son. He did not
want to become an employer. He wanted to
become what? A father. I'm not hearing
you.
>> So when this young man was a way off,
verse 20 says what? And the father saw
him. I'm not hearing you. I mean verse
20. So when he got up, he went to his
father. But while he was still a LONG
WAY OFF, HIS FATHER DID WHAT? SAW HIM.
THIS IS WHAT fathers ought to be. AND
FILLED WITH WHAT? COMPASSION. FOR HE RAN
at his SON, THREW HIS ARMS AROUND HIM,
AND KISSED HIM. HE DID not tell him,
"Take a bath, wash fast, go to the
shower. THIS IS MY SON."
Am I talking to somebody here?
AND THIS YOUNG MAN IS TRYING TO play
changing the roles. I know you are my
father, but I want you to become my
employer.
But the father said, "No, I am not."
Listen, am I talking to you? Cuz some of
you appear fathers, fathers, fathers,
>> fathers, IF THIS WAS YOUR SON COMING
BACK, SOME OF YOU would have behaved. I
would rather be your employer. From now
on, you are going to pay to stay here.
From now on, you are going to pay to
live in my house. Yes, I'll give you a
salary, but you've got to work for it.
That was the mistake of the older
brother. He thought he was working for
an inheritance. And the father said,
"No, no, no. If you are my son, all that
I have IS WHOSE IS YOURS." Luke 15:31,
"All that I have is yours. YOU ARE NOT
WORKING for it because YOU ARE MY SON."
MY SON, THE FATHER SAID, YOU ARE always
with me and everything I have is WHOSE
IS YOURS.
YOUR CHILD DOES NOT HAVE TO BRUSH YOUR
shoes
to get some pocket money. fathers.
I'm talking to fathers.
And because you carried a a box on your
head going to high school, your son must
also carry a box.
I'll ask all the men to stand
and I'll finish this message
and I'm trying to talk to you fathers,
ladies.
Mother's Day.
Are you understanding me? Now
>> you can see how the father behaves. He
telling the son, you know, I didn't lose
an employee. I lost a what? A son. An
employee will hire. That's a hirling.
And I'll pay him for his labor. You are
not a hirling in this house. You're not
looking for wages. You're waiting for
your inheritance. call for all that I
have is yours. That's what your children
should feel from you
>> as a father. That you are a provider.
Talk to me that you are a what? A
father. So he says, "Hey," he tells the
servants, he tell who? The servants,
bring the best robe, put on him. Bring a
ring, put on his finger. Talk to me.
Bring some shoes. Put on his feet.
Hallelujah.
>> What has he done? He's telling, "Hey,
son, I can give you a covering.
You are a protector. You are a
protector. Fathers,
where
we
are a protector. You are a what? You are
supposed to give your children a what? A
gathering.
Those hands are not supposed to beat
your wife, to beat your children. They
are for blessing.
[applause]
SO THAT EVERY TIME YOU LIFT UP YOUR
HAND, YOUR CHILDREN ARE GOING and your
wife is taking a step back cuz she knows
the last time you lifted your hand, she
received the what we call you laid hands
on her suddenly
or what pastor Tituso says, you gave her
five-fold ministry.
You're not supposed to give five-fold
ministry to your wife and children.
Let your children understand.
Can Am I talking?
>> WHEN MY FATHER LIFTS UP HIS HANDS, he's
coming to bless me.
>> You are a blesser.
>> You are a what? A BLESSER. GATHER BEFORE
[screaming] ME. GENESIS 49.
You sons of Jacob and listen to Jacob.
your father. Genesis 494:1. What does he
say? Genesis 4. And Jacob called for his
son. WHAT DID HE SAY? GATHER around so
that I can tell you what will happen to
you in days to come. Verse two. Does he
say assemble and listen sons of Jacob?
LISTEN TO YOUR FATHER ISRAEL.
A father is a prophet.
You should not be the one calling your
child queno
kubafu
useless gone case.
YOU ARE SUPPOSED TO BE A A PROPHET TO
your children.
A prophet prophesying comfort, strength,
ENCOURAGEMENT, BUILDING POSITIVE THINGS.
Some of the crisis we have in THIS
COUNTRY IS A FAILURE OF PARENTING. But
listen to me, a failure especially of
fatherhood.
AND WHEN FATHERHOOD FAILS THAT THERE'S
NOBODY can sit with their children and
tell them listen to the word of God,
listen to the Bible, listen to MY
INSTRUCTION, I GIVE YOU prophetic word.
We are failing IN OUR ROLE AS FATHERS IN
SOCIETY.
And as long as we fail as fathers,
I can assure you, we are going to
produce a generation that will not know
the God that we serve.
Are you understanding me, friends? So,
YOU'RE NOT JUST A PROVIDER, YOU'RE ALSO
A PROPHET.
Can I continue?
Could I continue?
>> Jacob failed in one area, very major
area. When they were coming back out of
uh from Laban's home, Laban was an idol
worshipper.
His daughters Rachel
and the sister Leia, they were idol
worshippers. So when they were COMING
OUT, THEY STOLE THE IDOLS OF THEIR
FATHER.
Jacob had NEVER TOLD THEM BEFORE I CAME
TO YOUR HOME THERE'S A GOD WHO MET me
and had made a vow
so by the time they are coming back
Rachel Leia the children
they did not know the God of their
FATHER SO INSTEAD OF going to back to
Bethl the house of God and the gateway
to heaven according to Genesis chapter
28 these that I did not know God was in
this place. That's what he confessed.
This is at this is the house of God and
the gh to heaven and he called the place
what? Bethl,
the house of God. He goes to a place
called Shem and he builds an altar to
himself
in Shem. You find that in I'm in Genesis
chapter 32 somewhere there. NOW WHEN HE
BUILDS THAT altar there and he forgets
about the God whom he had promised if
you bring ME BACK I'LL COME BACK TO THIS
PLACE AND BRING A TITHE to you.
Some of you your children know you're
not a tither
cuz you criticize me. You criticize the
pastors. You criticize when when we ask
for the tithe and your children hear
you.
It is in that place that his daughter
Diana was raped cuz there was no
spiritual cover. It is IN THAT PLACE HIS
SONS LEVI AND HIS BROTHER went and
killed a whole village,
tricked them to be circumcised. When
they were so they attacked them and
killed them. And Jacob said, "Oh, what
have you done?" HE HAD NEVER LED THEM to
an ALTAR WHERE JEHOVAH IS WORSHIPED.
FATHERS,
FATHERS, HAVE YOU LED YOUR CHILDREN TO
THE ALTAR WHERE JEHOVAH IS WORSHIPED?
That's when he lifted up his eyes and
wept. And God told him, JACOB, JACOB,
YOU ARE NOT SUPPOSED TO COME BACK HERE.
You are supposed to come BACK TO THE
PLACE WHERE I APPEARED to you. LISTEN TO
ME. THERE ARE FATHERS HERE. THERE'S A
PLACE WHERE YOU CRIED TO GOD. THERE'S A
PLACE WHERE YOU CALLED ON THE NAME OF
THE LORD. THERE'S A PLACE WHERE GOD
SPOKE TO YOU. THERE'S A PLACE WHERE GOD
GAVE YOU DIRECTION. THERE'S A PLACE THAT
CHANGED THE the trajectory of your life
and from that altar YOU HAD GOD AND YOU
ARE BLESSED AT THAT altar and you move
FROM THAT PLACE AND WAIT AND GOD
PROSPERED YOUR WAYS. AND now that you
are strong,
now that you are great, now that you
have got money,
is too far,
is too noisy,
is too dusty
or you are quiet.
So when you meet me, still ask me, do
you still go to Moa?
This is the altar. I'm not hearing you.
This is the altar where I met with God.
This is where God gave me promises. This
is where God changed my life. That's why
I still come back to this altar cuz this
is where I cried to God for my children
and I saw God bless them. I cried to Am
I right, church? Here. I cried to God
for my provision and I saw Jehovah Gyra
come through for me. Am I talking to
somebody here?
Don't raise an altar for yourself and
forget the altar where you called on the
name of the Lord when you are desperate
your father you are running away from
your brother running away from your
father your brother was trying to kill
you and God appears to you and tells you
Jacob
I shall go with you take you and bring
you back Jacob says you bring me back
here and I'll bring you a tithe
is that when he has to rise up and God
put the fear of God on the villagers
wanted to lynch them and Jacob laid his
few his wives and children out of
Sheckchim to go back to the house of God
and that's when he told him listen I
have a God who cannot stand idols get
rid of those idols he took all the idols
buried them under tree in shake and took
them back to God listen to me man of God
you are supposed to be a priest
they are no I say you are supposed to be
a priest.
>> Your children should see you pray. Your
children should hear you pray. Your
children should see you READ THE BIBLE.
THEIR CHILDREN SHOULD see you calling
them say, "Let's sit here. Open the book
of Psalms." WE ARE READING PSALMS 32
TODAY. LET'S READ IT. WHAT does it say
to you?
They should hear it from their father.
You want to surrender that to your to
your wife?
What are you doing?
Because we can can I continue?
>> Can I continue?
>> We can talk about that uh being a
prophet. We can talk about being a
priest and that's good and you should be
a priest in your home.
We can talk about probe being a
provider. That's all right. We can talk
about you a PROTECTOR AND THAT'S GREAT.
LOOK AT A MAN NEAR YOU AND JUST ASK THEM
for man. Man, ask them. Hey, gentlemen.
Are you a priest in your home? Are you a
provider in that home? Are you a
protector in your family? Are you a
prophet?
I come and deal with HIM MYSELF RIGHT
NOW because of absentee fathers.
Fathers who have refused to play their
roles.
Can I continue?
>> Can I continue? But there's a P that is
very missing my brother Gomi and that is
presence.
What? Presence.
You see you can say you are a provider
because you are sending empa
ladies. Ladies,
>> do you want empa you owe to the man?
and amen.
>> They want both. So yes, set that.
Now ladies, you're helping me preach.
[cheering]
Am I talking to somebody here?
It is very very important for us to
understand this.
Your presence, your presence, your
presence
as a father is required. Your presence
as a husband is important.
That's what you
Cuz
some of you are imagination is very
fatile.
Cuckoo.
How now? [laughter]
I love this church.
Are you understanding me now?
Change.
to find your wife standing on the coffee
table trying to change her about
it's an error
I like this church your your imagination
is very fatile
Your mind must be holy all the time.
Tell your neighbor presence
>> is very very and that is what is lacking
now
can I continue
fathers
Deuteronomy chapter 6 verse5
love the Lord Lord, you are not hearing
you. Love the Lord your God with all
your heart with all your soul and with
all your strength. Are you seeing those
words? I mean, go to verse six. These
commandments that I give you today are
to be upon your
>> push that man again. Talk to her. Tell
him man,
>> this instruction is for you.
Then why are you whispering now? These
instructions
are meant for the fathers.
>> are meant for the fathers.
>> In other words, you cannot preach water
and drink wine.
Children do not learn only by
instructions.
They learn by observation.
December,
my husband.
Hallelujah.
I write on my husband.
Your husband. I'm talking about these
children.
I'm al
because I'm your father.
That is not good enough anymore.
THESE COMMANDMENTS MUST BE IN your heart
and they must come out of your life
so that the genz's and the alphas can
observe them.
Many of us fathers, we are not
authentic.
And I've told this story before and I'm
taking tell it again because we are like
these fathers
who drinks whiskey and ram and brandy
when they at home. BUT IN CHURCH, GLORY
TO GOD,
they are ushers.
They sing in the choir in the men's
corel.
until the pastor went home to visit one
day. And when they were still not come
out, the small boy pulled a bottle of JB
Jnb whiskey.
I say, "Daddy."
SO WHEN THE FATHER COMES OUT OF THE
BEDROOM, HE FIND HIS son with his bottle
of whiskey.
Those are the people who know whether
you are born again or not.
Can I talk to you fathers? Can I talk to
you? Me? You can tell me. Praise the
Lord. I'll say amen. Cuz my work is to
give you the benefit of the doubt.
But you can, your children shall not
Your children want to see a present
father who is an example.
told you about a father who died
in London
and when they were holding a vigil for
him the choir from pastor Kamal's church
was there led by Paulin Camo they had
been leading songs one of the master of
ceremony says now we WANT TO SING THAT
SONG THAT he loved
and the choir stood up to sing that song
and they asked And the daughter said I
know I know I know I know.
So they asked they thought it will be
what a friend we have in Jesus.
The daughter said
how many of you know the choir sat down
because there are songs this side they
are not real. Can I talk to this side?
There are songs the choir cannot sing.
Look at that man. Ask him just today we
are talking to men.
>> When is mother's day I'll talk to the
mothers.
I know today can smile. Hey to me God
just mother's day I'm coming. Let's talk
to Can we talk to the men?
>> Fathers, can you can you talk to them
right now?
>> Talk to look for a man near you. Talk to
manto man ladies talk to a man near you.
Tell him
what model, what life are you modeling
before your children?
What are you modeling
this commandments?
This commandment
he says in verse seven, what does he say
to the fathers? I'm not hearing you.
What does he say? Impress them on who?
>> GO AHEAD. TALK ABOUT THEM when you sit
at home. When you walk along the road.
Continue.
>> And when you HOW MANY POSITIONS? FOUR
POSITIONS. You can count.
Are you getting me now? Talk about them
when you
>> when you
>> and when you
>> what the what is the first sentence?
>> SO THERE THE WAY YOU SHALL IMPRESS them
on your children is four ways.
Are you understanding me now?
When you are sitting at home, let them
hear you talk about these words.
When you are walking with them along the
road or when you leave, you are no more
regular life cuz that's your walk. Talk
to me.
CAN I CONTINUE? WHEN YOU LIE DOWN BEFORE
YOU GO to bed,
when you wake up in the morning. So the
question is, what is the last thing your
children see you do? What's the first
thing they hear you do? Talk to me.
Because some of you, THE ONLY TIME YOU
PRAY WITH YOUR CHILDREN IS FOR FOOD.
AMEN.
BUT THE LAST THING THEIR CHILDREN SHOULD
see you as you go into bed, can we sit
and read these words?
Hallelujah.
Can I continue? When you wake up in the
morning, yesterday I did a funeral of a
97 year old lady.
One of the daughters who are a pastor
said
whenever she visited her grandmother
in the morning she would hear cuz she
was already a widow. She could hear a
grandmother pray in a language that was
not English.
So she has a grandmother what language
do you use when you pray? Says that is
called speaking in tonesues.
Then the child as what is speaking in
tongues and the grandmother explained
today that girl is a Pentecostal pastor
because the first thing she heard her
mother do in the morning was to pray in
tongues.
What is the first thing they hear you do
in the morning to wake up where
where's my water?
Where's my blue socks?
>> [laughter]
>> The last thing at night.
Hallelujah.
Impress
them ON YOUR CHILDREN. HOW DO I IMPRESS
THEM? TALK ABOUT THEM. WHEN YOU DO WHAT?
Sit at home and when you walk along the
road and when you lie down and when you
get up,
TIE THEM AS A symbol on your hands and b
them on your forehead. Look at those two
words. That's another way of impressing
them. In other words, can I can I say
what that means? IN THE WORK OF YOUR
HANDS,
let the word of God be seen. In the way
you think,
be guided by the word of God.
WHAT? LET YOUR CHILDREN KNOW YOU ARE
earning honest money.
You are not a bribe taker.
You are not impressing them because you
are getting illicit money. You're not a
drug dealer.
That's the work of your hands. TEACH
THEM THE VALUE OF HARD WORK.
>> TEACH YOUR SONS AND YOUR DAUGHTERS THE
VALUE OF hard work.
Cuz they ARE COMING WITH A SENSE OF
ENTITLEMENT.
NO, these days pastor Oscar if you tell
your children the value of hard work
some will tell you oh that is child
abuse
whenever I wake up and I go we've been
staying with one of my grandsons as me
cooker you are still going he says I'm
still going what are you still going to
do I say I must work what do you mean
you must work so that you can eat
you are Here you are eating
and you're telling me not to work and
you're eating
but you've been working for a long time.
Yes. I'm trying to show you that in your
life you will work for a long time.
LET'S PREPARE THERE for a lifetime of
work.
BEFORE THERE WAS A FAMILY MAN was
working.
Can I say that again? Before Eve came in
his life, Adam was given work. Let us
teach our children the value of honest
hard work. Not hand out, not free
things,
not enter, not entitlement, not welfare,
not scams.
Am I Am I talking to you?
Many of us we've shown our children it
is easy to get money
but is here our
gear
take them there one time
Jesus was taken to the carpet reaction
that's why in Mark 6:3 they called him
is this not the carpenter
Is this in this the carpenter? CARPENTRY
IS HARD WORK.
Some of you are give your children so
much money
so early so that they think can I
continue that's why you can find them
saying
gadget
computer until you come back.
[clears throat]
My father
BY THE TIME SOME OF US were 19
leave not being shown the door we also
wanted to leave
by the time you finish from six never
wanted to go back home I'll tell you WHY
THERE WERE SO MANY CHILDREN THAT BACK
HOME there
by the time was finished FROM FROM SIX I
NEVER WENT BACK
I look for my friends. We went and hired
a room, be fellow believers, and we
started staying together, fending for
one another, learned the hard way.
That is Esther's room. That is Tiffany's
room. That is Jaden's room. Shut up. Fun
room.
Teach them the value of hard work. Teach
them to fend for themselves.
and start teaching them, putting in
their mind the right doctrine.
Now listen,
Greg Rolley say Greg Lori said you can
be a traditional dad and people may call
you old-fashioned, foolish because you
believe in discipline. Can I talk
correction and discipline? BECAUSE A
FATHER according to Hebrews chapter 12,
a father carries discipline.
Me I don't believe in disciplined
children. They can make their own
decisions. The Bible says foolishness is
bound in the heart of a child.
IF THEY KNOW EVERYTHING, WHY DO YOU take
them to school?
Take them to school because they don't
know mathematics. They don't know
geography. They don't know history.
Someone has got to give them put give
them instructions. Now those are
teachers. They are hired to give them
instructions. But at home who is giving
them instructions.
It is you are responsibly as a father to
give them instructions. And that's why
I've told you in this church and I'm
telling you again
say there in verse 12. Hebrews 12:9.
What does it say? Moreover, what does it
say? We all had what? Human fathers.
What did they do do us? They discipline
us and what we do. We respected them for
it.
Now,
if you discipline a child,
the lady we are laying to rest
yesterday,
his her own children who are very
successful
and grandchildren who are doing very
well, they told us even if you visited
her as grandchildren by 6 a.m.
[clears throat]
6.
IF YOU TELL SOME OF OUR CHILDREN THAT
now
because fathers fathers fathers we have
failed to discipline our children.
Well, Paul is very clear. The first
verse we read, children, obey your
parents.
Honor your father and mother. Well, that
is right. But for them to honor you, you
must be a person who gives instructions.
You must put put boundaries.
When I ra was raising my children, I was
very clear.
One of my instructions was this,
Jackson.
I must be the last person to come back
to this house. Nobody comes in after me.
We are not equal.
I'm the one who pays the rent, buys the
food, pays electricity, pays the water.
Me, I cannot come back at 7 and you are
coming back at 9:30. Hello my people.
You will discover we are not your
people.
So my children knew
daddy is the last one to come home. The
rest of us
put some boundaries.
WE ARE RAISING CHILDREN WITHOUT ANY
boundaries
on THESE GADGETS. PUT SOME BOUNDARIES.
You cannot SITTING A TABLE AND
EVERYBODY'S on a gadget.
You're not even talking.
Come on.
I said, "Come on, fathers."
I know they may call you oldfashioned,
but listen, I'll say that again. I'll
say THAT AGAIN. YOUR ASSIGNMENT AS A
FATHER is not to raise happy kids, but
to raise responsible adults.
Responsible adults are people who are
disciplined.
see sour
cuz these days you know SG when we were
growing up there's nobody we didn't have
rooms
cuz all of us shared rooms with our
brothers and sisters
I'm looking for some real people here
there was no room
in
a
So there WAS NOBODY COULD SAY THAT THIS
IS my room. Nobody.
That's how we grew up.
I'm in my room. Knock before you enter.
Knock before I enter.
Knock before you enter.
What do you mean knock before you enter?
I don't mind knocking. Do you understand
me now?
Hello. If you are a young adult, I'll
respect you. But you must grow up.
You cannot stay in your room the whole
day
cuz our assumption is that you are
sleeping. Then they say, "No, I was not
sleeping. I was just on my gadgets." How
can you watch reals on Instagram, Tik
Tok, Google, whatever for a whole day?
What are you learning?
What are you picking from X?
Fathers,
fathers, you are the ones who carry the
respect of discipline.
Put boundaries for your children.
Teach them, can I say? Teach them to
respect other people's property.
But the other way is not just by
teaching them and telling them. I want
to close by this by setting an example
modeling for them.
How do you handle their mother?
How do you handle them?
How do you handle conflict between you
and your wife and the children are
watching?
How do you handle hard times, difficult
times? Cuz they'll come and they come.
And some of you men, can I talk?
It is important your children know that
even you can be vulnerable.
Jesus wept.
They think I am weak.
television
model.
How do I handle grief? How do I handle
challenging times? How do I handle it?
Because I am in between jobs. Model
these things for your children because
those are the things
for a son cuz they are watching you.
So that is important. I want fathers to
come back. Come back in your presence.
Come back with your instructions. Come
back with with a modeling to your
children. Let them see.
Here you pray. Here you see read your
Bible. Read your Bible with them. Tell
them tomorrow I'll not read with you. I
want to continue reading. I'll ask you
the day after tomorrow. Model
and don't be afraid to correct them.
That's not right. You cannot come back
at this time. You need to come back
early. Give them some some
[clears throat] boundaries.
If friends come here, they are welcome
but they cannot go to bedrooms. You can
go sit here, can go to the to the
kitchen, can use THE BATHROOM, BUT
BEDROOMS ARE OUT OF PLAY, OUT OF BOUNDS.
YES, you can visit your friends, but you
must come back by 7:00. Your friends can
visit, but they must go back to their
homes by 7.
Am
I teaching you?
I'm not saying I'm not teaching this
saying, "Oh, Bishop Mind is a model."
I'm just I'm just I'm trying to tell
you, brethren, I've I've gone through
this.
I've raised children. I've raised
teenagers. I've raised young adults. Now
I'm living with the grandchildren. I
think there's a lesson I can teach you.
Are you understanding me now? I'm not
teaching this lesson as a a person who's
been married for eight years and my
children are five and six and I want to
write a book on parenting.
Hallelujah.
Amen.
They in their late teens almost 20.
So I can I can challenge you.
Have I have I had a trouble-free life
raising children? I can tell you no. Cuz
my children are normal children.
How did I know? They came back with red
lips and red tongues.
I'm closing with this. Train a child.
Train who? Listen, you don't train a
late teenager.
Don't start training when they're in
their late teens. Don't start training
young adults. Train a what?
1 to seven. This is the best time to
start training a child.
And to quote my friend Greg again, he
says he's quoting one of the Greek
philosophers. I think that was either
Aristo or the other secretist I think
Aristo who said give me a child of 1 to
seven years of age and I'll give you a
man.
What they pick between year 1 and year
seven that's what makes them the woman
they'll be and the man they will be.
What are they watching in your life?
What are you modeling? What are you
teaching? When are you training them?
Don't say this. Sunday school teacher
shall do it. Pastor Oscar shall do it.
I'll send them to
is not to raise your children
and you are some of the most difficult
parents.
You'll hear from my lawyers.
Let me just tell you this as I go to sit
down. Teachers now are operating from
hands off policy.
So I'm calling you fathers.
I want to pray for you
and I'm praying for you because I'm one
of you.
Father's Day is the most unseleelebrated
day in church calendar. Am I correct?
And I tell you why
I gave a warning to others. If you don't
celebrate Father's Day, there'll be no
other Mother's Days in this church.
pair of socks.
Happy Father's Day.
The thought counts.
[applause]
Husband, fathers, fathers, fathers, are
you here? The responsibility we have is
immense.
The priestly, the prophetic, the
provision, the protection. Are we there?
I say, are we there? And now the
presence that comes with sound
instructions.
It is the privilege of them being called
Mrs. Minde is very small. The majority
of what I have are responsibilities.
So amen, can we pray together? Look for
another man near you and just hold
hands.
You may have to move.
One of you may have to move. Just pick
one. Pick one. Don't pick. You can pick
three. Maximum three. But you pick one.
Don't go along the way you are going.
Yes. Yeah. Yeah. So yeah. Two. Two. Two.
Maximum three. Shall we do that? Ladies,
can you just bow your heads and pray for
these men? And you men, can you just
pray for one another in that group for a
moment? Lord, we bring before you these
men who are standing in this house. They
are the fathers of the current and the
next generation. And Lord, I pray for
them for the immense responsibility that
you have given TO THEM. THE IMMENSE
RESPONSIBILITY that you have given to
them to be priests, to be prophets, TO
BE PROVIDERS, TO BE PROTECTORS. AND NOW
WE ARE CHALLENGING them to be present in
the life of their children, to be
present in the lives of their family, to
be present as instructors and as models
for their children. Dear father, some of
us somewhere along the line as we listen
to these words, THERE'S A PLACE
SOMEWHERE WE FEEL WE FAILED.
We don't want to live in condemnation.
We come before and say, "Father, forgive
us. Father, forgive us." From today,
we'll take a responsibility. We shall be
protectors. We shall be prophets. We
shall be priests in this home. WE SHALL
BE PROVIDERS IN THIS HOME. But above
all, our presence shall be felt as we
model and as we teach and as we instruct
in the ways of the Lord. Help every
father watching listen to this telecast
in Jesus name. In Jesus name.
Have you learned something? Has the Lord
blessed you?
Let's be seated. The greatest model of a
father we have is the father in heaven.
The father in
>> that's a great model. If you are here
and you don't you don't know the
heavenly father. I would like to pray
for you and connect you with that
heavenly father because there are some
of you you didn't even grow up with a
father. So you don't need you don't even
even know your father. Therefore you're
telling me bishop
I never saw my father. THERE'S A
HEAVENLY FATHER who would like to
connect with you. If you are here and
you like to connect with the heavenly
father, just stand on your feet. Let me
pray for you. I'll so that you can
connect with the heavenly father. Where
are you? Tell me. I'd like to connect
with my heavenly father. My heavenly
father. Our heavenly father.
You don't know the heavenly father. You
can know him this moment.
Are you is that one coming?
Raise your hands towards me.
May you walk in the light of the
revelation you have received.
God is our heavenly father but down here
he has given us immense responsibility
as fathers
so that as our children pray our father
who is in heaven let them have a model
right here because I've got a father on
earth may our our fathers be a model of
the heavenly father in Jesus name in
Jesus name.
Ready to give? I'm ask you ready to
give.
>> Well, the choir will be singing as we
give offerings today to the glory of
God. Amen. Pastor Oscar, come and
pretend this. Pastor Oscar is pretend
this part. If there are any
announcements, he'll make announcements
then.
Let's begin. Pastor will tell you you
have a microphone.
Let's start moving to the closest
receptacles that is near you. As the
ushers and the elders wait on us,
[singing]
[music]
[music and singing]
>> [music]
[singing]
>> Bishop, Bishop, [music] Bishop, Bishop.
Shout
[music] out
[singing]
[singing and music]
Bishop Bishop
[music]
[singing]
[music] for way [singing]
[music]
[singing]
shall be
Bish. Bishop [singing]
[music]
Bish.
[singing]
[music]
>> [music]
[singing]
>> We shout you.
>> [music]
[singing]
>> Bishop, Bishop, Bishop.
[music]
>> [music]
[singing]
>> Bishop, Bishop, Bishop,
Bishop, [music]
Bish,
[music and singing]
Shall
>> [singing]
[music]
[music and singing]
>> shall be
shall
be shall be shall be
>> [music]
[singing]
>> single.
[music and singing]
Let's pray together. Heavenly Father, we
want to thank you uh for ministering to
us today and also want to thank you for
giving us an opportunity to worship you
with our giving. We want to commit this
to you that Lord you'd receive it. And
we pray for every hand that has been
able to give the Lord in blessing. Would
you bless them and minister to them this
week that this week will be better than
last week that they'll experience your
blessings and your protection and your
cover and to your glory and the honor of
your name and in Jesus name we pray.
Amen and amen and amen and amen. Thank
you. Thank you. Thank you Ashes. Thank
you. Thank you so much. Um we'll we'll
play the announcements. Uh if you have
any announcements uh the media team
please do go ahead and play that at this
moment.
>> Hello transformers welcome to
deliverance church international um the
center for transformation. The month of
June is our family month and we are
excited to have a wide range of
activities across our campuses to
celebrate our diverse families. Visit
the family life desk to find out how to
plug in.
The days of refreshing conference 2026
will take place from the 17th to the
23rd of August. Please plan to take your
leave and save the dates to attend this
convention where we feed from choice
servants of the Lord.
Vaua Camp for girls completing grade 9
in 2026 is set for the 16th to the 20th
of November 2026. The charges are 7,500
shillings to be paid via Empa pay bill
4002000
account 01128100998500.
For more information please contact
Moren on 0720-546217
or Celia on 0720884280.
The rights of passage organized by the
men's ministry for boys who have cleared
class 8 to undergo a medically procured
circumcision and teaching is all from
the 16th to the 28th of November 2026.
The venue will be Aesa Crest School and
the charges are 21,000 shillings per
student for the camp. This cost will
cater for accommodation, food and
doctor's fees. Payments should be done
via our empa pay bill 991648
account ros plus the [music] child's
name. You can begin to register and pay
in installments at the church reception.
Please obtain a receipt and maintain it.
For more information, contact Benson on
0792275454
or July on 0796775361.
All men who joined the pillars club are
reminded to redeem their pledges. You
can do so via our empa payel 991648
account.
Couples, are you ready for the great
escape? Join us from the 12th to the
15th of August at Mombasa Continental
Hotel to strengthen your marriages,
deepen intimacy, and be refreshed
[music] in God's presence.
>> Hey everyone, praise the Lord. I hope
you're doing well. Every couple in this
house, you need to know that there is a
great escape. You and your husband or
you and your wife, you need to give
yourselves a break. Just look for 60,000
bob to me.
Go down to Mombasa Continental Hotel
from the 12th to the 15th of of August.
You're going to have a great lineup of
speakers, time to meet with other
couples. Whether you've been married one
year, 60 years, you [music] can always
do with a refresh. And nowhere better to
do this than Mombasa. So I hope that you
make your time, take your tenttoawa.
So we'll see you at the great escape
Mombasa Continental Hotel from the 12th
to the 15th of August this year. [music]
Register now details below. God bless.
The charges are 60,000 shillings per
couple exclusive of transport. Please
[music] send your payment to Empa Pay
bill 991648
account retreat and your name.
All couples across all our campuses are
warmly invited to a [music] special
couples gathering today at your
respective campus as we culminate our
family month. This will be a beautiful
time of fun and intentional
conversations [music] as we pursue
oneness in our marriages. The time will
be communicated by your respective
campus leaders.
The Champions Fellowship will have a
meeting on the 5th of July at Umoja 3
campus from 12:30 p.m. This is a
fellowship that brings together parents
of differently aabled children and
support structures within DCIU.
As part of the DelQ 2026 strategic plan,
we have launched a short survey aimed at
improving new member registration to
help us serve you more effectively.
Please scan the QR code and fill in the
questionnaire.
Deliverance Church International Omoa is
looking for a procurement officer.
Interested candidates should send their
applications and CV to reach the church
office by Friday the 3rd of July at 5:00
p.m. Applications can be handd delivered
or emailed to info@ dcumoja.org.
For more details about this vacancy,
please visit the notice board next to
the information desk.
That is it from the media team. Do have
yourself a blessed week ahead.
Pillars Club
roof.
They still connect with us through our
refreshing time program. NTV gave us the
same rate we are getting at K24 for the
next two years.
So I need you to commit yourself to the
pillars club just by a thousand
shillings a month.
We are doing this in Mombasa. We are
doing Mombasa road k road KCC
is there.
There's a barcode. So get that barcode.
Can you get that bar?
come here.
This elder is one of the leaders in our
men's fellowship. He's got the barcode.
Connect with him your barcode. You
register yourself and be sending your
contribution monthly. Just a thousand
thousand
bless.
Thank you so much. um shortly will be
releasing us. Just to remind you guys,
are we getting into July? August. August
we start our days of refreshing on the
17th of August. We're telling you so
early so that you can get some time and
be with us. 17th of August. That week is
a days of refreshing week. Make sure you
diarize that. But then this week
critical tomorrow we have our prayer
meeting starting at 6:30. And then
Tuesday, Wednesday, Thursday and Friday
we have our Bible marathon. uh we
normally do the journey then uh pick up
on the Bible marathon. So to starting
Tuesday you want to be part of the Bible
marathon and then tonight at 3 p.m. not
tonight at 3 p.m. again as a campus you
gather together. All camp couples in
this church if you're married please
come with your spouse just for an easy
time of sitting together getting to know
one another and we'll be able to
introduce to you some of the things that
we want to do as couples in this church.
This is part of the family month. You
want to make sure that you come. Um
finally, I don't want to ask you to be
upstanding. I'll call later shakam. I
will receive the visitors. But then as
you stand, please remember um if you are
a visitor, I know you've gotten a call
or a text. You've been a visitor in this
church um for the last three months.
That's April, May, and June. Uh today we
gather at the tent after this service.
So don't just go home. Go to the tent on
my left towards the ablution block. Our
hospitality team is there. Prepared
something for you just to get to know
you more and get to plug you in into
some of the activities in this church.
So if you've been a visitor uh for the
last three months, you got a call, you
got a text. Please don't just dash home.
Let's walk towards that tent and I'm
sure that God will bless us. So don't
forget Tuesday Bible marathon all the
way to Friday. Don't forget 17th of
August, we have our days of refreshing.
And don't forget tonight at 3 p.m. uh we
have our couples gathering in this
place. Amen. Uh Latasha, has she led as
well? Please appreciate these young
girls. She's going to receive our
visitors and then uh we'll be moving
from there.
>> Thank you so much, Rev. Oscar. Let's
appreciate Rev. Oscar one more time.
Thank you so much.
Uh we've come to the end of our service
and just before we close, we love to
receive our visitors in the house today.
So if it's your first time visiting us,
you can raise your hand. We just want to
receive you and fellowship with you for
a few minutes before you go home. Any
visitors?
Any visitors?
Church, you can help me if there's a
visitor. If there's someone you've come
with today, you can just walk with them
to the front so that we receive them and
pray for them. Is there any visitor?
Wow.
Please come to the front. We'll just
love to receive you and pray for you and
thank God for you. Any other visitor?
Amen. Let's appreciate him until he gets
here.
Thank you so much.
Amen.
We're so glad to have you. and on behalf
of our bishop we like to receive you to
deliverance church if you're looking for
a church.
Amen. Uh so please let's stretch our
hands even as we pray for our visitor
today.
Lord we thank you for our visitor. We
thank you king of glory for leading him
here this morning. My king of glory I
pray in the name of Jesus Christ. Oh God
Lord if he's looking for a church to
fellowship in may he find a home at
Deliverance Church. Omo I pray that Lord
you may bless him. Oh God, if he's
visiting, oh God, we pray that Lord, he
will go back, oh God, uh with our
greetings and with our blessings, oh
God. And Lord, we thank you for him, oh
God. May you bless him. May you bless
his family and may you bless all his
endeavors, oh God, in Jesus mighty name
we pray and believe. Amen. Thank you so
much. Uh please follow the lady. Uh she
will receive you and tell you more about
our church. Amen. Have you been blessed
today? Have you been encouraged? The
Bible says, "And now that you know these
things, you'll be blessed if you do
them." So we are not only hearers of the
word, but may we become doers. Amen.
Amen. And now may the grace of our Lord
Jesus Christ and the love of God and the
fellowship of the Holy Spirit be with us
now and forever more. Amen. Have a
blessed week and remember to join us
tomorrow for